Antoanet Azhib Brand Strategist

Hi! I'm Antoanet - a brand strategy consultant with 6+ years of experience in communications, with a spark for behavioural science, deciphering human irrationalities and decision-making. Inquisitive, positive and relentlessly curious, I love delving into unconventional questions, challenges and points of view, seeking ways to improve both myself and the world around me.

Skills Summary

Brand & creative strategy
Consumer & cultural trends
Behavioural change & insights
Market research & analysis
B2C & B2B experience

Work Experience

Brand Consultant at Radley Yeldar Jan 2022 - present

- Leading the strategic development on key agency accounts, including Syngenta, GSK and ViiV Healthcare
- Specialising in brand strategy and proposition development
- Developing clear briefs to inform and guide the creative process
- Working cross-departments, supporting our sustainability and digital teams on ongoing projects and pitches
- Bringing in a psychology and human insights-led approach to brand and campaign development, as well as client outreach
- A champion for behavioural science in the agency, supporting on behavioural change projects as needed, including work for WRAP and Recycle Now

Strategist at Gyro UK (now Merkle B2B) Sept 2019 - Dec 2021

- Worked directly with the Head of Strategy on key client accounts, including Goldman Sachs, JLL, Fujitsu and Brother
- My day-to-day included insights gathering, competitive analysis, brand and audience research, and identifying category codes & conventions to inform strategic direction
- Facilitated workshops and key stakeholder interviews

Strategic Planning Graduate at Publicis UK Sept 2017 - Apr 2019

- Worked with strategy directors to guide strategy and creative on global agency clients across FMCG, automotive and financial sectors. Clients included Nescafe, Purina, Renault and Airbus.
- Uncovered consumer & behavioural insights and provided strategic direction in pitches as part of the New Business team
- Helped organise agency events and client trainings on behavioural change, behavioural economics and lateral thinking

Work Experience (Outside of UK)

Previous experience in account management and client-side June 2013 - May 2015

Prior to graduating and moving to London, my advertising and communications journey started out in Sofia, Bulgaria. Working full time between semesters and part-time during the academic year while at university allowed me to experience various sides of marketing, brand and comms very early on in my career. It gave me a better understanding of the industry in general, which in turn has made me into a better strategist and consultant.

Some of this work experience includes:

- Account management in a small creative boutique
- Social media & content strategy in a medium-sized digital advertising agency
- Client-side marketing internship at the biggest telecommunications company in Bulgaria

Educational History

New Bulgarian University /NBU/ Advertising BA

Oct 2011 - March 2016

- Graduated with a grade equivalent of a First
- Core Advertising program with a focus on human behaviour and decision-making, including courses on social psychology, sociology, consumer behaviour, psychology of persuasion
- I completed my degree with an additional semester of research on the topic of Behavioural Science and writing my bachelor's thesis - "Fundamental principles of Behavioural Economics and their application in Marketing and Advertising"

Achievements & Training

- Applied Behavioural Economics IPA certification (2020)
- Behavioural Science for Brands certified by WARC and Cannes Lions (2019)
- Behavioural Economics, Behaviour Change and Frameworks --MINDSPACE and COM-B training (2018)
- Advertising Academy Team mentor in an annual student advertising competition, organised by New Bulgarian University and the Bulgarian Association of Communications Agencies (2018, 2019, 2020)
- Clearcast Training (2018)
- YouTube Creative Essentials (2018)

Contact me at:

+447565064691

antoanet.azhib@gmail.com

http://linkedin.com/in/antoanetazhib/